The solver will find the nodal temperatures
using a procedure similar to what we saw in the Big Ideas and in FEA.
So it&#39;ll go from the boundary value problem
to a system of algebraic equations in the nodal temperatures.
And it&#39;ll do that using the piecewise polynomial approximation for T I
just talked about.
And each algebraic equation will relate a nodal temperature to its neighbors.
For instance, if I consider this particular node, when
the solver derives the algebraic equation for that node,
it will relate this node to the nodal temperature.
Let&#39;s say if this is 3, it&#39;ll relate T3 to the neighboring temperature values.
And to see which temperatures will be related,
we can use a principle that I discussed in the Big Ideas.
So you look at all the elements that are attached to that particular node.
So we have four elements attached to that node.
And then you pick out all the nodes that are attached to each of those elements.
So this element is attached to these four nodes,
this element is attached to these four nodes.
And then you have these nodes coming in and these nodes,
which means that the algebraic equation at this node
will relate T3 to these other values.
This node is not connected to this element,
so for instance, those nodes won&#39;t be involved in writing that relationship.
And we also know that there&#39;s going to be a constant term, that constant heat
generation.
In this case we don&#39;t have heat generation,
so the algebraic equation at this node won&#39;t contain any constant term.
And once the solver generates those algebraic equations-- in fact,
it thinks of fit as in the matrix form, the temperature vector, for instance,
in this case will be-- you know, I have 16 temperature values.
So this be a vector with 16 rows in one column.
The stiffness matrix will be a 16 by 16 matrix, and so on.
And similarly you can think about what&#39;s the dimension of Q?
And it&#39;ll invert that, so that&#39;s a matrix inversion problem,
and determine the nodal temperatures.
So you&#39;ll have the 16 nodal temperatures,
and everything else is calculated from those nodal temperature
through post-processing.
So for instance, you can find the temperature at any location
through the interpolation from the nodal temperatures,
and then you differentiate that, you can get the heat flux.
And the heart of the method is going from the differential equations
to a system of algebraic equations.
Let&#39;s think about how the process that we discussed in the Big Ideas and FEA
gets extended to the 2D case.